Kyle Sorensen

2876 S 3350 W, Hurricane, Utah | 7605196870 sorensen.kyle@pm.me

Summary

I am a software engineer with 7+ years of experience working in the scientific industry on embedded projects and AI, along with 4+ years of full stack development using Python/React. I have extensive experience with AWS, along with proficiency in Azure and GCP, CI/CD, Test driven development, agile methodology. I am self-taught and always hit the ground running.

Experience

Kungfu AI | TX, Austin

Software Engineer (Contract) | 04/2022 - 11/2022

Worked on a team of 2 MLEs as a software engineer to build a restful API using FastAPI around a computer vision model to an embedded edge device, containerized this API using Docker.

agilon health | CA, Irvine

Senior Cloud Engineer | 03/2021 - 04/2022

Worked with a team of 10 other software engineers to move a data warehouse and collection service off MSSQL/.NET and into Python3/AWS/Snowflake. Built a restful API service using AWS lambda for the submission and retrivial of medicare eligibility inquires to the govt.

Mori Associates / JPL | CA, Pasadena

Systems Monitoring Engineer (Contract) | 04/2020 - 02/2021

Rewrote an old enterprise web application in React/Python and deployed this to NASA's Kubernetes cluster. Developed applications to assist in the monitoring of critical network operations at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory. Developed an automated, unsupervised, time-series anomaly detection service for JPL's network telemetry data.

Grokstream LLC | CA, San Clemente

Senior Software Engineer | 03/2017 - 03/2020

Worked in a team of one other software engineer (the CTO), and an MLE to develop a large scale anomaly detection framework, along with a network event clustering model, which were combined into a web based front end, for the automatic detection of severe incidents in large network operations centers. Developed a front end web application in React/Flask to visualize and explore data.

Thermo Fisher Scientific | CA, Carlsbad

Software Engineer (Contract) | 10/2016 - 03/2017

Worked as a contractor on a team of 3 other engineers to develop embedded software to run on Thermo Fisher's DNA sequencers, with the purpose of integrateing their collection, experiment and metadata to an AWS cloud environment.

3 Screens Studios | CA, Escondido

Software Engineer | 03/2015 - 06/2017

Worked with a team of 2 other developers to maintain and build a web application for a client to monitor drug and bodily fluid samples in real time as they were processed through their lab. Additionally, worked on a small project that created a Google chrome plugin to study the effects of search engine results during the 2016 US election.

Skills

Linux, AWS, Azure, Docker, Elasticsearch, Kubernetes, Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Embedded, Physics, Wilderness Survival, Poetry, CNNs, JavaScript, React, Vue.js, Python3, Flask, FastAPI

Education

California Polytechnic State University - San Luis Obispo | San Luis Obispo, CA

Physics

Studied a B.S. in Physics.

College of the Sequoias | Visalia, CA

Completed coursework necessary to transfer to a 4-year university.